

SUMMARY

Dynamic and forward-thinking recruitment specialist offering a broad experience in identifying, recruiting, and hiring highly-skilled employees. Hired majorly for IT and Non-IT roles in Accounts and Finance, Sales, Customer Support, Data Engineering, Data Analytics, Data Science, QA, RPA Developer, Business Transformation, Foreign languages and many other roles.

EDUCATION

- MBA (HR and IT) From Kashmir University in 2018.
- B.com from Kashmir University in 2015.
- ❖ 10 + 2 (Commerce) from JK Bose in 2012.

TOOLS USED

- ❖ Naukri.com
- Workday
- Jobdiva
- LinkedIn
- Avature
- ❖ Abacus
- ❖ Taleo

MOHAMMAD ASGAR JAN

€.





6006622738

asgarmohammad833@gmail.com

Delhi, India

WORK EXPERIENCE





RECRUITMENT SPECIALIST

'22 Jan 2020 till 11 July 2020' '13 Mar 2021 till 27 March 2023'

- ➤ Collaborating with the hiring managers for the hiring demands and ensuring that the hiring needs are met and running effectively.
- Sourcing potential candidates from Naukri.com, LinkedIn and referrals and sharing them with the hiring managers for the hiring demands.
- > CV screening/reviewing and shortlisting the HR ok candidates and showcasing them to the hiring managers.
- ➤ Hired candidates for different verticals, like Fin Tech, HMS, BCM, CGRLH, Corporate, Hitech and Insurance.
- ➤ Managed end to end recruitment from Sourcing till onboarding of the candidate.
- > Documentation of the shortlisted candidates.
- > Negotiating the salary with the shortlisted candidates.
- > Releasing the offers for the selected candidates.
- Proper engagement with the candidates so as to avoid any offer drops.

Accenture accenture

'25 May 2023 till 7 Sep 2023'

- ➤ Analyzed and evaluated company employment needs, screened and reviewed all Resumes/CVs, cover letters, and applications, and conducted interviews.
- Identified and attracted potential job candidates, trained and placed new personnel, and was responsible for multiple recruitment functions.
- ➤ Launched and coordinated various events, represented company at job fairs, and worked on the development and implementation of a new and more efficient hiring strategy to minimize recruitment expenses.
- ➤ Posted job advertisements, supported the HR Managers with various tasks as assigned, and assisted in the creation of a new corporate training program.
- > Recognized by executives and colleagues for performing excellent work and achieving great results.

Skills

- Sourcing
- Candidate Assessment
- Negotiation
- Employer Branding
- Recruiting
- ❖ ATS
- Team Managemnet

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 1st Jan, 1995

Father's Name: Mr. Mohammad

Maqbool Jan

'18 Jul 2024 till Now'

- ➤ Proficiency in assessing candidate qualifications, potential and cultural fit to ensure optimal hiring decisions.
- > Strong verbal and written communication skills for effectively interacting with candidates, hiring managers and other stakeholders.
- Expertise in using various sourcing methods and recruitment platforms to attract top talent.
- > Proficiency using ATS to track candidates through the hiring process, ensuring efficient candidate management.
- > Skilled in conducting various types of HR interviews to gain comprehensive insights into candidates' capabilities.